Guide to the Radical and Labor Pamphlets Collection, 1896-1967, bulk 1911-1954 RL.11741
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Anti-Fascist and Pacifist Radical Movements, 1933-1951 and undated, bulk 1930s-1940s; 25 pamphlets
  - Germany, Hitler and the Trade Unions, undated [use copy] (Box 7)
  - Germany, Hitler or Lenin, undated (Box 7)
  - The International Brigades, Commissariat of War. These Men Have Died, undated (Box 7)
  - Sefarov, Georgii I. The Far East Ablaze, undated [use copy] (Box 7)
- Left-Wing Radical Organizations, U.S.A., 1930-1943 and undated, bulk 1930s; 18 pamphlets
  Pamphlets sponsored by various other organizations such as International Labor Defense, the International Workers of the World, and the "Wobblies" (Industrial Workers of the World), written by various authors or published anonymously. Published chiefly during the 1930s.
  - International Labor Defense, 1930-1943
    - Engdahl, J. Louis. Sedition! To Protest and Organize Against War, Hunger and Unemployment, 1930 (Box 8)
    - Colman, Louis. Night Riders in Gallup, 1935 (Box 8)
    - Colman, Louis. Voices from Prison, 1935 (Box 8)
    - Soule, Isobel W. The Vigilantes Hide Behind the Flag... [introduction by Vito Marcantonio], 1937 (Box 8)
    - Soule, Isobel W. The Work of the International Labor Defense for Aid to Labor's Prisoners..., 1937 (Box 8)
    - Victory in Oklahoma over Hitlerism in America, 1943 (Box 8)
    - Goldman, Albert. Charge: Rioting. Verdict: Not Guilty!, undated (Box 8)
    - Ryan, Paul W. The C.S. Case Against Labor: The Story of the Sacramento Criminal Syndicalism Railroading, [circa 1936] (Box 8)
  - Industrial Workers of the World ("Wobblies"), 1921-1934
    - William, George. The First Congress of the Red Trades Union International at Moscow, 1921..., [1921?] [use copy] (Box 8)
    - One Big Union of All the Workers, the I. W. W., 1933 (Box 8)
    - Unemployment and the Machine, 1934 (Box 8)
    - Giant Industry and the I. W. W...., undated [use copy] (Box 8)
    - William D. The General Strike, undated [use copy] (Box 8)
    - One Big Union of All the Workers, the IWW, undated [use copy] (Box 8)
    - Smash the IWW - Remember!, undated [use copy] (Box 8)
  - Other Organizations, 1922-1932
    - General Defense Committee, International Workers of the World. An Open Letter to President Harding, [1922?] (Box 8)
    - National Committee of Unemployed Councils. Why We March for Unemployment Insurance, 1932 (Box 8)
    - Revolutionary Workers League. Why the Revolutionary Workers League, undated (Box 8)
- Communism, Great Britain, 1924-1957; 57 pamphlets
  - Communist Party of Great Britain, 1924-1957 and undated, bulk 1940s-1950s
    Written by members of the Communist Party of Great Britain or published anonymously. There are thirteen pamphlets by Harry Pollitt, the Party's General Secretary. Arranged alphabetically by last name or title.
    - Audit, George. Egypt and the Labor Government, undated (Box 9)
    - The Battle of Ideas: Six Speeches on the Centenary of the Communist Manifesto, 1948 (Box 9)
    - Burns, Emile. The Triumph of Communism..., 1948 (2 copies) (Box 9)
    - Campbell, John R. A Socialist Solution to the Crisis, undated (Box 9)
    - Clegg, Arthur. 5 Years against Japan: China the Unconquerable, [1942?] [use copy] (Box 9)
    - Clegg, Arthur. Hands Off Indonesia, 1946 (Box 9)
    - Clegg, Arthur. American Spider, 1947 (Box 9)
    - The Communist Party of the Soviet Union: Syllabus for Six Lectures on the History of the C.P.S.U ..., 1942 (Box 9)
    - The Communist Party of the Soviet Union: Syllabus for Six Lessons on the History of the C.P.S.U, 1949 [use copy] (Box 9)
    - Communist Party Pamphlets, 1956 (Box 9)
    - Communist Theory Series, no. 2. Course for New Members, undated (Box 9)
    - Communist Theory Series, no. 3. The Development of Socialist Thought, undated (Box 9)
    - Communist Theory Series, no. 4. The Party and its Work ..., undated (Box 9)
    - Daily Worker Defense League, London. The "Daily Worker" and the War, undated (Box 9)
    - Draft Political Resolution, 1957 (Box 9)
    - Essentials for a Health Service..., 1946 (Box 9)
    - For Marxist-Leninist Education, No. 1 of a Series of Four Lesson Courses...Socialist Construction in the Soviet Union, undated (Box 9)
    - Fyfe, James. Lysenko is Right, 1950 (Box 9)
    - Gallacher, William. William Gallacher's Speeches in Parliament, 1938 (Box 9)
    - Gallacher, William. The Merchant Navy..., 1943 [use copy] (Box 9)
    - Gallacher, William. What is Democracy? 1945 (Box 9)
    - Gollan, John. Why the Food Shortage? 1946 (Box 9)
    - Gollan, John. Towards Communism, 1952 (Box 9)
    - Jeffery, Nora. Bring Down the Food Prices! 1953 [use copy] (Box 9)
    - Jeffery, Nora. Lancashire, 1848-1948..., [1948?] (Box 9)
    - Montagu, Ivor G. S. The Federal Union Myth, 1940 (Box 9)
    - Montagu, Ivor G. S. Stalin: A Biographical Sketch of the Man Who Leads the U.S.S.R., 1942 (Box 9)
    - Nottingham Marxist Group. Why We Left the Communist Party, [1956?] (Box 9)
    - Paul, William. Atomic Energy and Social Progress, 1946 (Box 9)
    - Pitcairn, Frank. Where France Begins: What I Saw in Algiers, [194-?] (Box 9)
    - Pollitt, Harry. Which Way for the Workers?... [1932?] [use copy] (Box 10)
    - Pollitt, Harry. Can Conscription Save Peace? 1939 (Box 10)
    - Pollitt, Harry. How to Win the War, 1939 (Box 10)
    - Pollitt, Harry. Deeds -- Not Words! 1942 (Box 10)
    - Pollitt, Harry. Why You Should Be a Communist, 1945 [use copy] (Box 10)
    - Pollitt, Harry. Britain Will Make It, 1946 (Box 10)
    - Pollitt, Harry. Communist Policy for Peace: Negotiate Now, 1951 (Box 10)
    - Pollitt, Harry. Why Britain Needs the Communist Party Today More than Ever, 1951 (Box 10)
    - Pollitt, Harry. The Nazis Shall Not Pass! 1952 (Box 10)
    - Pollitt, Harry. A Policy for Labour, 1952 (Box 10)
    - Pollitt, Harry. What Do Miners Need? 1953 (Box 10)
    - Pollitt, Harry. In Defense of Peace: The Case Against Re-Arming the Nazis, 1954 (Box 10)
    - Pollitt, Harry. The Path to Peace, undated (Box 10)
    - Robson, R. W. Communism: An Outline for Everyone, 1943 (Box 10)
    - Robson, R. W. Proud Record .., 1942 [use copy] (Box 10)
    - Robson, R. W. Why We Talk Politics, 1942 (Box 10)
    - Rust, William. The Inside Story of the "Daily Worker." Ten Years of Working Class Journalism, [1939?] (Box 10)
    - Rust, William. Lift the Ban on the Daily Worker, [1942?] (Box 10)
    - Rust, William. Victory Year, 1945, [1945?] (Box 10)
    - Rust, William. Where Is Germany Going? [1946?] (Box 10)
    - Scotland's Schools: A Memorandum ..., [1939?] (Box 10)
    - Scottish Agriculture. Memorandum ..., undated (Box 10)
    - A Study Guide: The Cooperative Movement, 1948 (Box 10)
    - A Study-Guide to the Communist Manifesto, 1948 (Box 10)
    - The Transition to Socialism: A 3-Lesson Syllabus, 1948 [use copy] (Box 10)
    - Varga, E. The Decline of Capitalism, 1924 (Box 10)
  - Young Communist League, 1929-1952
    - Stand Ready!... 1929 (Box 10)
    - Eastwood, Fred. Youth and the Trade Unions, 1942 (Box 10)
    - Moss, John. Free Britain's Youth..., 1952 (Box 10)
    - Cohen, Gerry. Socialism! The Future for Youth, undated (Box 10)
- Communist International, 1932-1946; 12 pamphlets
  Two pamphlets are published by the organization itself, while a group of others was written by Georgi Dimitrov, the head of Communist International. Most of the pamphlets concern fascism and the party platform.
  - Communist International. Theses and Resolutions..., [1932?] (Box 11)
  - Communist International. Principles of Party Organisation: Thesis on the Organisation and Structure of the Communist Parties..., undated (Box 11)
  - Georgi Dimitrov. Dimitroff Accuses, 1934 (Box 11)
  - Georgi Dimitrov. Dimitrov: His Final Leipzig Speech Accuses, 1934 (Box 11)
  - Georgi Dimitrov. The Legal System of German Fascism: Reply to Herr Ribbentrop, 1936 (Box 11)
  - Georgi Dimitrov. Fascism is War, 1937 (Box 11)
  - Georgi Dimitrov. To Defend Assassins Is to Help Fascism, 1937 (Box 11)
  - Georgi Dimitrov. The Soviet Union and the Working Class of the Capitalist Countries, [1937?] (Box 11)
  - Georgi Dimitrov. The Guarantee of Victory, 1938 (Box 11)
  - Georgi Dimitrov. After Munich, 1939 (Box 11)
  - Georgi Dimitrov. George Dimitroff, with an Introduction by Earl Browder, 1943 (Box 11)
  - Georgi Dimitrov. Laski's Mistake: Dimitrov's Speech in Full... Forward by Harry Pollitt, 1946 (Box 11)
- Communism, Other Countries, 1930-1954; 12 pamphlets
  Pamphlets issued either by the Communist Parties in countries other than the U.S. or Great Britain, or pamphlets published in the U.S. that discuss communism in the world. Countries represented are Australia, Brazil, Canada, China, India, Ireland, Italy, and Mexico.
  - Militarist Wars and Revolution in China, 1930 (Box 11)
  - Communist Party of Ireland, Inaugural Congress, 1933. (Box 11)
  - Ireland's Path to Freedom: Manifesto of the Communist Party of Ireland, [intro. by Sean Murray], 1933 (Box 11)
  - Madden, Marie R. Communism in Mexico, 1936 (Box 11)
  - Prestes, Luis Carlos. Luis Carlos Prestes: The Struggle for Liberation in Brazil, 1936 (Box 11)
  - Communist Party of Australia, General Committee. Constitution and By-Laws, [1938?] (Box 11)
  - Lift the Ban on the Communist Party of Australia Conference, 1942 (Box 11)
  - Fajon, Etienne. Les communistes et la propriété: conférence prononcée le 6 décembre 1944, Salle des Sociétés Savantes, [1945] [use copy] (Box 11)
  - Communist Party of Australia, 14th Congress, 1945. Communists in Congress, 1945 (Box 11)
  - Communist Party of India. Declaration of Independence..., [1946?] (Box 11)
  - Gronchi, Giovanni. Communism Versus Freedom: Which Way Italy? 1948 (Box 11)
  - Wei, Chen [pseud]. Who's Who in Communist China..., 1954 (Box 11)
  - Smith, A. E. Communist Illegality and the New Minister of Justice, Canada, undated [use copy] (Box 11)
- Communism, General, 1918-1950; 18 pamphlets
  - Leon Trotsky and Trotskyism, 1931-1950
    Five of these pamphlets were written by Leon Trotsky, while the other four are written by various authors and concern Trotskyism
    - Trotsky, Leon. The Revolution in Spain, 1931 (Box 12)
    - World Unemployment and the Five Year Plan, 1931 (Box 12)
    - Andrews, R. F. The Truth About Trotsky, 1934 (Box 12)
    - Dunne, William and Morris Childs. Permanent Counter-Revolution: The Role of the Trotzkyites in the Minneapolis Strikes, 1934 (Box 12)
    - Goldman, Albert. "Trotsky's Widow Demands Stalin and Others Be Brought Before Mexican Court," 1947 [news release] [use copy] (Box 12)
    - Trotsky, Leon. Trade Unions in the Epoch of Imperialist Decay [intro. by H. A. Vardhan], [1947?] (Box 12)
    - Grant, Ted and Jock Haston. Behind the Stalin-Tito Clash: Trotskyist Analysis, 1948 (Box 12)
    - Trotsky, Leon. The Lesson of Spain: The Last Warning!, 1948 (Box 12)
    - Perspectives of World Development, 1950 (Box 12)
  - Bolshevism, 1918-1950
    - Novosseloff, S.S. The Bolsheviki and the American Aid to Russia ..., 1918 (Box 12)
    - Nikiforov, Peter. The Strike of the Dredging Fleet, 1905, 1931 (Box 12)
    - Bobrovskaya, C. [comp.]. Ivan Babushin: A Short Biography, 1932 (Box 12)
    - Kedrov, M. S. Book Publishing Under Tzarism, 1932 (Box 12)
    - The Moscow Trial, Authentic Report: The Indictment, Proceedings, Prosecutor's Speech, Defense, the Verdict, the Red Paper (Litvinov) [N. P. Vitvitskii and other employees of Metropolitan-Vickers, defendants], [1934?] [use copy] (Box 12)
    - Joffe, Adolf A. The Last Words of Adolf Joffe: A Letter to Leon Trotsky, 1950 (Box 12)
    - Bobrovskaya, C. Provocateurs I Have Known, undated (Box 12)
    - Moorahtoff, Dimitry. Bolsheviki, undated (Box 12)
    - Sprenger, Rudolf. Bolshevism: Its Roots, Role, Class View, Method [trans. by Integer], undated (Box 12)
- Anarchism, 1896-1940; 10 pamphlets
  Pamphlets by various authors concerning anarchist movements; there is also a eulogy of Emma Goldman. Pamphlets written by Emma Goldman are grouped separately.
  - Tcherkesoff, W. Let Us Be Just: An Open Letter to Liebknecht, 1896 (Box 12)
  - James, C. L. Origin of Anarchism, 1902 (Box 12)
  - Durant, William J. Socialism and Anarchism, 1914 (Box 12)
  - Grosser, Philip. Uncle Sam's Devil's Island, [1931?] (Box 12)
  - De Cleyre, Voltairine. Anarchism and American Traditions, 1932 (Box 12)
  - Weinberger, Harry. Emma Goldman [speech delivered at her funeral], 1940 (Box 12)
  - Labadie, Joseph A. Anarchism: What It Is and What It Is Not, undated (Box 12)
  - Emma Goldman. The Individual, Society and the State, 1930s (Box 12)
  - Emma Goldman. Trotsky Protests Too Much, 1938? (Box 12)
  - Emma Goldman. The Truth about the Bolsheviki, 1918? (Box 12)
- Labor Unions, U.S.A., 1911-1956; 74 pamphlets
  - Labor Organizations, 1911-1956, bulk 1930s-1950s
    Arranged alphabetically by name of organization, then by date.
    Materials regarding labor and trade unions in the United States.
    - American Anti-Boycott Association. Coercion of Congress as Attempted by Organized Labor, undated (Box 13)
    - American Federation of Labor. Standards for Compensation Legislation, 1925 (Box 13)
    - American Federation of Labor. The People of America Can't Forget, [195-?] (Box 13)
    - American Federation of Labor. Today's Forgotten People, [195-?] (Box 13)
    - American Federation of Labor, Free Trade Union Committee. Why Communist China Should Not Be Admitted to the United Nations, 1954 (Box 13)
    - Association· of Workers in Social Agencies. Spies, Dismissals, Discrimination..., 1935 (Box 13)
    - Committee for May Day -- 1948. March for Peace, 1948 (Box 13)
    - Congress of Industrial Organizations, California CIO Council. The "Perfect Crime" of Mr. Taft and Mr. Hartley, 1947 (Box 13)
    - Council of Machinists. This Is FDR..., [1944?] (Box 13)
    - Dress and Waist Manufacturers' Association. Protocol of Peace Between the Dress and Waist Manufacturers' Association and the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union, 1913 (Box 13)
    - Farmer Labor Political Federation. The Farmer Labor Political Federation, [1934?] (Box 13)
    - Farmers' National Conference. Farmers' Call to Action, 1933 (Box 13)
    - Farmers Unite Their Fight, 1933 (Box 13)
    - Federated Press, Inc. Why FP? What Every Labor Editor Should Know About Labor's News Service, undated (Box 13)
    - Food, Tobacco, Agricultural and Allied Workers Union. Who's UnAmerican!..., [circa 1947] (Box 13)
    - Food, Tobacco, Agricultural and Allied Workers Union. Your Union, How to Make It Strong..., [1950s?] (Box 13)
    - General Labor Union. Unity in Action, 1932 (Box 13)
    - General Relief Committee -- Textile Strikers. The Textile Strike of 1926, 1926 (Box 13)
    - Industrial Union of Marine and Shipbuilding Workers of America. Book of Facts for Shipyard Workers, [1935?] (Box 13)
    - International Brotherhood of Teamsters. The Name Is Hoffa, 1956 (Box 13)
    - International Federation of Architects, Engineers, Chemists, and Technicians. The Technician's Primer on Federal Civil Service Litigation, undated (Box 13)
    - International Longshoremen's Association. The Maritime Crisis: What It Is and What It Isn't, undated (Box 13)
    - International Longshoremen's and Warehousemen's Union. The Everlasting Bridges Case, 1955 (Box 13)
    - International Oil Worker. It Happened in California, undated (Box 13)
    - International Union, United Automobile, Aircraft, and Agricultural Implement Workers of America. Become a Citizen! How to Do It, 1943 (Box 13)
    - International Union, United Automobile, Aircraft, and Agricultural Implement Workers of America. Discrimination Costs You Money, undated (Box 13)
    - League for International Rights. Regulation of Labor Unions..., 1937 (Box 13)
    - Motor Carrier Association of New York. Five Year Peace Pact and Code of Procedure, 1954 (Box 13)
    - National Association of Die Casting Workers. Labor and Production, undated (Box 13)
    - National Maritime Union of America. The Seamen Answer Standard Oil's Lies, undated [use copy] (Box 14)
    - Oil Workers International Union, C. I. O. How to Speak at Union Meetings, undated (Box 14)
    - Red International of Labor Unions. The Constitution of the Red International, 1921 (Box 14)
    - Retail Drug Employees Union. So You Have a Right!, undated (Box 14)
    - Steel Workers Organizing Committee. Steel Profits and Your Wages, [1936?] (Box 14)
    - United Association of Journeymen and Apprentices of the Plumbing and Pipe Fitting Industry. The Kohler Worker's Story, undated (Box 14)
    - U.S. Mutual Security Agency. The Working People of Europe, undated (Box 14)
  - Signed Pamphlets, 1911-1955
    Arranged alphabetically by author's last name, and within those groupings, by date.
    Among the authors are Philip Murray, John Llewellyn Lewis, and Walter Philip Reuther, all well-known labor leaders.
    - Cahn, Williams. Frankly Sir, I Need More Money!, undated (Box 14)
    - Cahn, Williams. Mill Town: A Book You Will Never Forget, undated (Box 14)
    - Claessens, August. A Manual for Trade Union Speakers, undated (Box 14)
    - Deverall, Richard L-G. The Democratic Revolution ... Free Trade Unionism, 1950 (Box 14)
    - Filley, Jane. Consider the Laundry Workers, 1937 (Box 14)
    - Flaherty, Viva. History of the Grand Rapids Furniture Strike with Facts Hitherto Unpublished, 1911 (Box 14)
    - Goldberg, Louis P. Next Step American Labor? 1952 (Box 14)
    - Gordon, Louis. The White Collar Workers Organize, [1938?] (Box 14)
    - Green, William. President Green Sounds Warning Against Continued Existence of Committee for Industrial Organization, undated (Box 14)
    - Green, William. What Unions Do for the Community, undated (Box 14)
    - Hanson, Rudy. What About Finland? undated (Box 14)
    - Hartwell, Al. You Can Only Win With Wallace, [1948?] (Box 14)
    - Lewis, A. L. Too Much Is Much Too Muehl, undated (Box 14)
    - Lewis, John Llewellyn. A Timely Message from John L. Lewis, 1936 (Box 14)
    - Lewis, John Llewellyn. Jobs, Peace, Unity, 1940 (Box 14)
    - Lewis, John Llewellyn. Main Address at the Ford Local 600 Anniversary, 1951 (Box 14)
    - Morris, George. Labor Unity: What AFL-CIO Merger Means for Workers, 1955 (Box 14)
    - Murray, Philip. The CID Defense Plan, [1947] (Box 14)
    - Murray, Philip. Prices and Wages, 1943 (Box 14)
    - Murray, Philip. Steelworkers Need a $2.00-a Day Wage Increase, [1947] (Box 14)
    - Murray, Philip. The Case for Labor, 1947 (Box 14)
    - Murray, Philip. The Union Shop?...Yes, But There Are Other Major Issues ..., 1952 (Box 14)
    - Murray, Philip. Save Small Steel ..., undated (Box 14)
    - Murray, Philip and Vincente Lombardo Toledano. Labor's Good Neighbor Policy..., undated (Box 14)
    - Muste, A. J. The South as Labor's Battleground, 1929 (Box 15)
    - Page, Dorothy Myra. It Happened on May First!, [1940] [use copy] (Box 15)
    - Pressman, Lee. Profits vs. Pay, 1945 [use copy] (Box 15)
    - Reuther, Walter P. How to Raise Wages, 1945 (Box 15)
    - Reuther, Walter P. Address by CID President, Walter Reuther..., 1953 (Box 15)
    - Reuther, Walter P. We Shall March Together, [1953] (Box 15)
    - Rosenblum, Frank. Less Hysteria, More Democracy, 1951 (Box 15)
    - Schneiderman, William. The Pacific Coast Maritime Strike, 1937 (Box 15)
    - Shepard, Seth. Dissenting Opinion of Mr. Chief Justice Shepard, undated (Box 15)
    - Snook, J. To Hell with War, undated (Box 15)
    - Standard, William L. The Coming Ship Subsidy Scandal, [1937] (Box 15)
    - Standard, William L. Merchant Seamen and the Law, 1946 (Box 15)
    - Zugsmith, Leane. L is for Labor, undated (Box 15)
- Labor Unions and Labor Parties, Great Britain, 1917-1951; 12 pamphlets
  Among others, the following political parties are represented: the Labor Party, the Independent Socialist Party, and the Socialist Labor Party.
  - Grigg, Joseph W. The Workers' Resolve: An Interview with WA. Appleton, 1917 (Box 16)
  - Labor Party. British Labor Party Program of Reconstruction, 1918 (Box 16)
  - Higginson, P. R. A Suggested Basis for the Discussion of One Union for Railway Workers [forward by G.D. H. Cole], 1924 (Box 16)
  - Mosley, Sir Oswald and Oliver Baldwin. Social Revolution in England, 1929 (Box 16)
  - MacDonald, James R. A Prosperous Countryside, 1930 (Box 16)
  - Morrison, Herbert S. London Under Socialist Rule, 1935 (Box 16)
  - Montagu, Ivor G. S. Zero Hour, Second Front [appendix by Ilya Ehrenberg], [1942?] (Box 16)
  - Conservative Political Centre, London. The Growth of the Trade Union Movement, [1951?] (Box 16)
  - Morris, Will. Co-ops and the War, undated (Box 16)
  - Riddick, W. A Short Primer of Industrial History, undated (Box 16)
  - Russell, Betty. After Rockets, Housing Rackets ..., undated (Box 16)
  - Transport Workers International, Propaganda and Action Committee. Bevin and Wilson, undated (Box 16)
- Labor Unions, Other Countries, 1924-1959; 12 pamphlets
  Organizations in Canada, China, Ireland, the Philippines are represented here, as well as several international organizations.
  - Irish Transport and General Workers' Union. The Facts Concerning Larkin's Departure to America... [reprint from The Voice of Labour, Apr. 12, 1924], [1924?] (Box 16)
  - Pan-Pacific Secretariat of Transport Workers. Against Imperialism, [1929?] (Box 16)
  - Pan-Pacific Trade Secretariat. The Class Trade Unions of Japan ..., [1934?] [use copy] (Box 16)
  - International Confederation of Free Trade Unions. For Bread, Peace and Freedom, 1949 (2 copies) (Box 16)
  - Hernandez, Amado V. Philippine Labor Demands Justice, [1949?] [use copy] (Box 16)
  - Saillant, Louis. The Workers Strengthen United Action and Develop Their Activity in Defence [sic] of Their Economic and Social Interests... [meeting of the World Federation of Trade Unions, 1951, Vienna], 1951 (Box 16)
  - Free China Labor League. A Brief Survey of Taiwan Labor Movement and Labor Conditions, 1952 (Box 16)
  - International Confederation of Free Trade Unions. Another Hoax: An Exposure of the WFTU Charter of Trade Union Rights, 1955 (Box 16)
  - Morris, Leslie. Labor-Farmer Political Action, [Toronto, Canada; Labor­ Progressive Party], 1959 (Box 16)
  - International Confederation of Free Trade Unions. ICTFU: Free Trade Unions of the Whole World March Together Towards a Better Life for All, [1954?] (Oversize-folder 1)
  - Canadian Seamen's Union, National Office. The C.S.U and You. The Case For Free Trade Unionism, undated (Oversize-folder 1)
- Socialism, U.S.A., 1897-1957; 79 pamphlets
  - General, 1897-1954, bulk 1897-1919
    One pamphlet was written by Eugene Debs, Socialist Party leader, and another by Jack London, American writer and social activist. Several pamphlets in this series discuss women's issues.
    - McCall, Erwin. The Martyrdom of Percy Whitcomb, Socialist and Agnostic, [1897?] [use copy] (Box 17)
    - Wanhope, Joseph. The Division of Wealth, [1900?] (Box 17)
    - Hagerty, Thomas J. Why Physicians Should Be Socialists, 1902 (Box 17)
    - Richardson, Noble Asa. Introduction to Socialism, 1902 (Box 17)
    - Methods of Acquiring National Possession of Our Industries, [1903?] (Box 17)
    - Debs, Eugene V. The Federal Government and the Chicago Strike, 1904 London, Jack. The Tramp, 1904 (Box 17)
    - Lewis, Arthur M. and Job Harriman. Lewis-Harriman Debate Socialist Party vs. Union Labor Party, 1906 (Box 17)
    - Osborne, John B. Hearstism: An Analysis of the Government Ownership Question, 1906 (Box 17)
    - Common Sense. Appreciations, a "Common Sense" Bug Booklet with an Appreciation from Our Gene by A. Corey and Alfred G. Sanftleben of the "Common Sense" Staff, 1907 (Box 17)
    - Russell, Charles E. Socialism and the National Crisis, [1910?] (Box 17)